Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
upper intermediate level lesson
about something very technical.
We're talking about
marketing strategies here today.
That's right, today we
have an upper intermediate
lesson at the office,
that is the category
of this lesson and we're basically talking
about marketing, a marketing plan and a lot
of technical words around
this part of business.
Alright, so let's take a
listen to today's dialogue and
we'll be back in just a moment
to talk about what's going on.
Okay everyone, let's begin.
I called you here today to evaluate our
marketing strategy during this recession.
I wanted to re-emphasize
our corporate mission
of aiming to give our
customers the best coffee
in service in a clean and
welcoming atmosphere.
Several other shops
have been reducing their
prices for their coffees and they
are drawing in more customers.
Why aren't we doing the same thing?
I know that recent
sales have been slow but
we are not going to reduce our
prices to the level of our competitors.
We offer a superior
product and our focus is
on long term growth
rather than short term sales.
If we lower our prices we run
the risk of devaluing our product.
Customers don't care about coffee
anymore, they only care about price.
I disagree, highly
discerning customers know
that our coffee is far better than
the coffee you buy at the other places.
Our coffee beans are
artisan roasted and we use
state-of-the-art equipment
to brew our coffees.
When you compare the coffees side by side
our coffee wins the taste test every time.
We have never sought to
appeal to the mass market
with cheap coffee drinks
and we will not do so now.
That's true, we've
certainly achieved top of
mind awareness when it
comes to the best tasting
brews and it's important to distinguish
ourselves from the competitors.
I think the main question is how can we
show our appreciation to our customers?
That's the main question I
would like to discuss today.
Money is tight for
everyone these days, so even
our most loyal customers
may be reconsidering
the money they pay
for their morning coffee.
Since the security of
our coffees is one of
our core competencies, why don't we sell
the beans for people to brew coffee at home?
That could definitely be
a way we could expand
our company, but would we be undermining
the essence of the company that way?
Let's brainstorm some more
ideas and do some research.
The customer always comes first and
what the customer wants, the customer gets.
Maybe it's time we
started selling coffee beans.
Alright, we're back, so a
very interesting dialogue.
I think this is something
very common that
would go on in a meeting
room when the marketing
department is talking about prices and how
do we increase sales, etcetera, so I think
we had a lot of
difficult words or maybe
words that we didn't
really understand well,
so let's take a look at some
of those in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word on the top
of our list today is recession.
Anyone looking at the
news this year or last
year probably knows what this word
means, but let's talk about it anyway.
What is a recession?
That's right.
So everyone was talking about the recession
and basically it is a noun, alright?
And it means that
people don't have enough
money like before and
so consequently, services
or decrease, people aren't
buying as much, so there is a lack of
commerce going on in a
country, a region, or a city, etcetera.
Alright, so basically in economics
you have these different cycles.
It's not like the economy
is always the same
and so sometimes
when there's not enough
money we call it a recession and we can say
hey, I don't have much money to spend right
now, we are in a recession, so that's
a very common way to use the term.
That's right, so as you said, it's an
economic term and many consequences because of
this lack of jobs, it's
just as you said, a cycle.
And so apart from a
recession that that's why
they are brainstorming
to see how they can
increase sales despite
the recession, they also
talked about their customers and that
their customers are highly discerning.
Alright, so this word
discerning comes from
the verb to discern and
it's a really important
one because it means to
be able to tell the difference,
to understand the difference
between two different things.
Okay, so let's say we
have two cups of soda,
I'm very good at tasting things so I can
discern the difference, I can discern the
difference between these two, I can
say one is Coca-Cola and one is Pepsi.
Okay, so to discern
is to be able to tell the
difference or to notice
the difference between
many things and so obviously
you are a discerning person.
Alright, or you have discerning taste, this
means that you're very good at telling when
something is high quality
and when it's not high quality.
Okay, and we're talking
about discerning customers
who know what they
want and so they talked
about their coffee beans and
it's one of their core competencies.
Okay, so this is something
you might actually
hear in education
as well as in business.
Something is your
competency if you are able to
do it, alright, so I am
able to write Chinese
characters, it's one of
my core competencies,
okay, so that's
something that I'm able
to do so I consider it one of these central
or important abilities, but you always talk
about competencies
within the context of some
area, so my language
skills or in this case
at a company we're
talking about making a
coffee, one of the
companies core competencies
is making their coffee beans,
that's something they're good at.
That's right, and core,
when we talk about
core we talk about the center, we talk
about one of the most important things.
That's right.
Okay, and well for
the last word that we've
prepared to you in
language takeaway, we talked
about them worrying
that selling the coffee
beans might undermine
the essence of the company.
To undermine, okay,
this is a really important
verb, and you'll
hear this a lot actually
in TV shows and especially
in dramas, say he's
undermining my authority
or he's undermining
my power, this means
that someone is challenging
it or someone is kind of
taking it away from you.
Okay, so to undermine
is to, as you said,
challenge or try to take something from
you, very sneaky, in a sneaky way sometimes.
That's right, so for
example, if I'm the
president of a country
and someone is trying
to take that away from
me, someone is trying
to be the president
and trying to take down
my government, he is trying
to undermine my power.
Okay, very good.
So four keywords there
on language takeaway,
now we're going to
move on to fluency builder,
so we prepared a lot of
nice and very good phrases.
Fluency Builder.
All right, so on fluency
builder, why don't
we start up from the
beginning of the dialogue
when they were talking
about the prices of
the coffee and that
other shops have reduced
their prices and so they're
drawing in more customers.
All right, so the key here is to draw in,
this is a phrase, most people will know the
word to draw, you know,
to make a design on a page.
But to draw in has a very special
meaning, it means to attract.
Okay, so you want to
attract more customers,
you want to bring them into the
shop, so you're trying to draw them in.
So Marco, what's a good
example of something
that a company will do to
try and draw in customers?
For example, many of
you maybe have seen in fast
food restaurants when
they have a promotion,
like you buy one hamburger
and you get another one for free.
So that's maybe one
of the strategies that
they're trying to do to
draw in customers and
maybe not make money, but give people
the opportunity to taste their good food.
That's right.
All right, so the next phrase
we've got here is a little bit different.
It's a talking about
the kind of product that
they have, they're
talking about their coffee
beans and they say that
they're roasted and that they
use state-of-the-art
equipment to brew the coffee.
So this phrase, state-of-the-art.
What does this mean?
Okay, if something is
state-of-the-art, okay.
We're usually talking
about a machine and we're
saying that it's the
latest in technology.
It's very, very new,
it's highly advanced,
it's a very technologically
advanced machine.
So for example, the
new iPhone 4 is a
state-of-the-art cell
phone, that means it's
the very highest that
technology has to offer.
And obviously, something
that is state-of-the-art
is not state-of-the-art
forever because technology
changes and so maybe next year there
will be a new state-of-the-art telephone.
That's right.
So, if you notice the
spelling as well, we have
little hyphens between
each word state-of-the-art
because we take it as a
chunk altogether, right?
That's right.
And following that, we have another
phrase that is used to talk about products.
They say, when you compare
the coffees, we have side-by-side.
Our coffee wins against our
competitors, so side-by-side.
Okay, the phrase there
is side-by-side and they're
talking about comparing
coffees side-by-side.
So I think this is pretty
literal, it's basically
saying you put two
coffee mugs or coffee
cups together side-by-side
and you have people
taste and then you see
which one they prefer.
That's right.
So you can say this when
you're making comparisons.
When I look at them side-by-side, I think
I like the pink one more than the red one.
So you are comparing,
you're literally putting
them next to each other to make a
choice of which one is your preference.
That's right.
Now moving on, we
have a very interesting
phrase when they were
talking about the company
and they've achieved top of mind awareness
when it comes to best tasting brews.
So this phrase, top of mind awareness,
very closely related to marketing.
What are we talking about here?
Well, let's look at the individual words.
We have top, which is
on top, not on bottom,
mind, which is your
head or your thinking
and awareness, which is
the way that you see things.
And so let's take a guess here and say that
when I think of a category of product, like
coffee, for example, what is the
first thing that comes into my mind?
That's right.
So it's actually a very cool game that
you can sometimes play with friends.
Basically just say, okay,
when you think of coffee,
what is the first brand
that comes into your mind?
Starbucks.
For example, shows that Starbucks has
put in you a certain top of mind awareness.
You associate coffee with
Starbucks immediately.
You don't say, cost of coffee, you don't
say coffee being or any other brand, right?
No, yeah, no, definitely.
This is a way for you
to really test what
companies, what corporations
have the most effective
marketing because obviously they're
the ones who make you think of this thing.
That's right.
Starbucks has tons of marketing campaigns.
That's actually very interesting.
So you can say top of mind or
you can say top of mind awareness.
You can say Honda has great
top of mind among their clients.
Or Ferrari has great top of
mind among luxury vehicles.
That's right.
Okay.
And now for the last
phrase when we talked about
money again, this is
a very nice colloquial
way of saying that you don't have a lot of
money or money is very scarce right now.
All right.
So the phrase is money is tight.
That word tight, you can hold
something tightly or this belt is tight.
I'm gaining weight.
But in this case, money is tight.
That's a phrase we take as a chunk.
And it means like you say, Marco, I
just don't have much money right now.
So money is tight right now.
Mm hmm.
Now it's interesting
because you can say it,
money is tight and then the subject,
money is tight for bill right now.
Or you can say bill is tight
for money at the moment.
So you can switch it up
depending on where you put
the subject towards the
end or in the beginning.
All right.
So usually you hear
the phrase, money is
tight right now or money is
really tight just kind of on its own.
And it's a way to say, I
don't have much cash.
That's right.
Okay.
So we've taken a look at a
lot of words and phrases here.
Let's listen to our dialogue again.
And we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
Okay, everyone, let's begin.
I called you here today to evaluate our
marketing strategy during this recession.
I wanted to reemphasize
our corporate mission
of aiming to give our
customers the best coffee
in service in a clean and
welcoming atmosphere.
Several other shops
have been reducing their
prices for their coffees and they
are drawing in more customers.
Why aren't we doing the same thing?
I know that recent
sales have been slow,
but we are not going to reduce our
prices to the level of our competitors.
We offer a superior
product and our focus is
on long term growth
rather than short term sales.
If we lower our prices,
we run the risk of
devaluing our product customers
don't care about coffee anymore.
The only care about price.
I disagree highly
discerning customers know
that our coffee is far better than
the coffee you buy at the other places.
Our coffee beans are
artisan roasted and we use
state of the art equipment
to brew our coffees.
When you compare the coffees side by side,
our coffee wins the taste test every time.
We have never sought to
appeal to the mass market
with cheap coffee drinks
and we will not do so now.
That's true, we've
certainly achieved top of
mind awareness when it
comes to the best tasting
brews and it's important to distinguish
ourselves from the competitors.
I think the main question is how can we
show our appreciation to our customers?
That's the main question I
would like to discuss today.
Money is tight for
everyone these days, so even
our most loyal customers
may be reconsidering
the money they pay
for their morning coffee.
Is this a purity of our coffee beans
is one of our core competencies?
Why don't we sell the beans for
people to brew coffee at home?
That could definitely be
a way we could expand
our company, but would we be undermining
the essence of the company that way?
Let's brainstorm some more
ideas and do some research.
The customer always comes first and
what the customer wants, the customer gets.
Maybe it's time we
started selling coffee beans.
All right, so going back
to top of mind awareness,
let's test what brands
are in your head.
Okay, so for example, when you think
of a luxury sports car, what do you think?
Ferrari.
Ferrari, you mentioned it before.
Or Lamborghini.
Or Lamborghini, but you said Ferrari first.
When you think of a brand of
cigarettes, what do you think?
Camo.
Okay, this is an American brand.
It's very, it's found a very
commonly in other places.
They have it in Europe.
It's very popular.
Oh, really?
Yep.
Okay.
What about when you think of computers?
What do you think?
For some reason, IBM.
IBM.
Even though you don't own an IBM.
I don't, but I grew up
around the IBM revolution.
Okay, see, this is interesting.
So actually, it doesn't
always work that way
that because you have
a brand in your mind,
it doesn't necessarily mean that you will
purchase it in the future if you have the
power to, but at least you are aware
of the brand and you recognize it.
And the chances are that you will buy it.
That's right.
And you're going to
be familiar with it when
you read about it or, you
know, when people talk about it.
So, for example, I own a Mac
computer, you know, Apple.
But when I think of
computers, I just think
of IBM because we used to
say, remember, IBM compatible.
Now, that's right, IBM
compatible, because
before it was usually just
Mac, everything was for Mac.
Mac or IBM.
And then all of a sudden, it's PC or Mac.
Right, right.
Actually, that's
interesting though, because
if probably, if I say,
what do you think
of when you think of what brand comes
to mind when you think of MP3 players?
Apple.
Yeah.
If you probably think iPod, that's
probably one of the most famous ones.
But maybe if you asked
somebody about 10 years
ago, when you think about a music
player, what do you think about?
Sony, the Sony Walkman.
Yeah.
The Sony Walkman, right?
Or the Sony Discman.
That's right.
Head both.
It was like, I have a Walkman.
It was bright yellow.
So this is really interesting.
This is the way that you see more or less.
You can start to realize what brands are in
your mind and maybe unconsciously, even you
may not even be a
smoker, but maybe some
sort of cigarette brand
will be in your mind
or maybe you don't
really really like sports
cars, but you will have a
sports car brand in your mind.
I'm very curious to hear what you guys have
to say, because obviously, the brands that
we're aware of are
dependent on where we
come from and the marketing
campaigns in our home countries.
That's right.
And also our age, you
know, I was a teenager
when I had the Sony
Discman, so that made
an impact on me, but let's
throw that out to you guys.
Let us know what you
think of when we say, you
know, luxury cars or
MP3 players or computers
or maybe even basic
things like detergents.
For example, if you have somebody in
the United States, they might say tide.
But if you have somebody
in South America, they might
say, I don't know, o-m-o,
it's some type of brand.
So this is also very interesting to see
what your local brands have been doing.
That's right.
So let us know what you're thinking.
We're on EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right.
Bye.
[MUSIC]